Mohammed Maher Mosul, Nineveh/ Iraq Mobile: +964-771-799-2452

Email: mm91ed@gmail.com

Thursday, 21 August 2021

DATACODE B80, FLOOR 20, MRF 2 TOWERS, ENGLISH VILLAGE RD, ERBIL, KURDISTAN, IRAQ

Dear Hiring Team

I came across a post on LinkedIn stating that you have multiple job vacancies. I write to introduce myself as a potential future team member.

I enclosed my resume for your consideration, but of particular relevance is my experience in building web applications (using Angular, React, NextJS, NodeJS and NestJs), deploying applications on the Google cloud platform, designing relational (SQL) and NoSQL databases, and Linux server administration.

I would welcome an opportunity to meet with you at your convenience to discuss what I could contribute to Datacode..

Yours sincerely

Mohammed Maher

Mohammed Maher Web developer

Contact Mohammed Maher

Mosul, Nineveh/ Iraq +964-771-799-2452 mm91ed@gmail.com

Summary

A passionate developer with hands-on experience building the server-side application using NodeJS, deployment, and testing of applications on cloud computing platforms (Google cloud, Digitalocean), designing and modeling data on both relation (SQL/MySQL) and document-based (NoSQL/MongoDB), and Linux server administration and configuration.

Skills and Experience

Server-side

 Build production-ready server-side applications using modern technologies (NodeJS, NestJS)

Data modeling and database design

- Design and implement data models solutions, which include the use of relation (SQL) and NoSQL databases (MySQL, MongoDB)
- Work experience using the Elastic Stack which is a distributed search and analytics engine for all types of data.

Client-side

 Design and build client-side applications including admin dashboards using web technologies and modern frameworks (Angular, React).

Reports and data visualization

- Write scripts to analyze and transform data for reports generation in standard formats (PDF, spreadsheets)
- Data visualization using D3.js library.

Clouding computing

 Deploy and test applications on cloud computing platforms (Google Cloud, DigitalOcean).

Systems administrations

- Install and configure Linux systems (Ubuntu).
- Perform system maintenance.
- Provide technical support and guidance.

Mohammed Maher Web developer

Employment

Apr 2021 to Jun 2021 Trainer

Fikra Space

Trained a group of 15 people on the subject of full-stack web development for 12 weeks. The Bootcamp covered many topics, including the front-end side, back-end side, database design, and server administrations.

Jan 2019 to Nov 2020 We

Web developer

Mosul University

In this role, my key responsibilities were:

- Designed and built online forms for data collection.
- Implemented dashboards for accessing and manipulating collected data.

May 2020 to Jul 2020

Back-end developer

Dakakenna

Dakakenna is an e-commerce platform that delivers goods to residents in Mosul.

In this role my responsibility was to build a full-text search engine using Elasticsearch.

Nov 2016 to Dec 2018

Lab Assistant

Mosul University

In this role, my key responsibilities were:

- Provided timely technical support to faculty, staff and students.
- Helped the students who were struggling with the assigned tasks.

Apr 2016 to Current

Web developer

Freelance

In this role, my key responsibilities are:

- Discuss requirements with clients.
- Make website development proposals, design page layout.
- Write the code for the server-side and the client-side.
- Design the databases.
- Test and deploy the applications on the cloud.
- Provide maintenance and technical support.

Mohammed Maher Web developer

Projects Coviru

AL Dawa Ltd

One of the freelance projects that I have worked on. It is a
web-based solution for managing the data of COVID-19
tests for AL Dawa Ltd. It has over 30 active users distributed
across multiple labs. It currently holds test data for over 1
million patients.

- It has a convenient dashboard for adding, deleting, and updating data for patients, users, and labs. The users are divided across three different levels or groups. With each group having specified permissions. Users can generate on-demand reports and download them in excel spreadsheet format.
- I have built the backend side using NodeJS/NestJS, the front-end side using Angular, and the database using MongoDB. The application was deployed and currently running on the Google cloud platform.

Education University of Mosul

Bachelor of Software engineering

Languages English, Arabic, and Turkish (Intermediate Turkish)